Koome Mwiti

Site Reliability Engineer

kmwongera@icloud.com

Github: komerela

972 Mission St, San Francisco, Ca 92555

Career Objective

Site Reliability Engineer (SRE) trained as a software engineer with 7+ Years of non-traditional technical background in project management and digital communications. Growing at wepay where engineers can make ecommerce seamless would be deeply rewarding by improving the future of transactions.

Technology Stack

Docker, RevDeBug, MySql, Python, Datadog, MySql

Technical Skills

- ★ Programming Languages: C, D, Python, Javascript, Node.js, regex, perl, puppet, ruby
- ★ Software tools: Unix/Linux, Docker, Visual Studio, Vim, RevDebug, Test Driven Development (TDD) using Python module Doctest

Experience

Code for San Francisco / Volunteer Software Engineer

August 2019 - PRESENT, San Francisco, USA

NLP - Working with a team of civic hackers to develop a more efficient way of analyzing social media using Natural Language Processing (NLP) to improve transit in San Francisco

Neverest LLC / Automation

June 2017 - PRESENT, REMOTE - Kenya

- ➤ Initiated & led Test Driven Development (TDD) of M-lami app
- ➤ Product managed the development of <u>Karitela</u> Food delivery app
- ➤ Led the development of health care database management platform for Arizona Based Healthcare company's Pastalino Manor LLC

Amazon/ Process Assistant

February 2016 - November 2017, Riverside, California

- Designed & led the process for maximizing departmental productivity by 70% by implementing a workable LSS project in the outbound department
- ➤ Increased the morale of direct reports and eventually leading to the lowest departmental employee turnover in the facility

Other Experience

Well Told Story/ Head of Outreach & Head of Content

Nov 2010 - May 2015 - Kenya

Education

Holberton School of Software Engineering

2019 - San Francisco

- $\succ \quad \mathsf{Full}\,\mathsf{Stack}\,\mathsf{Software}\,\mathsf{Engineering}\,\mathsf{Program}$
- Site Reliability Engineering

Management & Strategy Institute / Lean Six Sigma Black Belt

> CERTIFIED PROCESS ENGINEER - September 2017, USA

United States International University - A (USIU)/ Bsc. IBA - Finance

April 2008, Kenya

AWARDS - 2012 International Emmy Award Winner, 2015 TEEP Winner for Anti-counterfeit Android Product